wsdonline.com 2015-03-30

# World Shipping Directory - Privacy Policy

The following on-line Privacy Policy, which complies with the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998, is designed to inform you on how Lloyd's Register - Fairplay Ltd collects and uses personal information. [**www.wsdonline.com**](http://www.wsdonline.com/) is owned and operated by Lloyd's Register - Fairplay Ltd., the leading supplier of maritime information services. 

**Personal Information**

As well as details of pages visited we collect information on where visitors are connecting from including the Internet Protocol address. This information is used for statistical analysis to determine how [**www.wsdonline.com**](http://www.wsdonline.com/)[](http://www.fairplay.co.uk/default.aspx) is used to help us improve our web offerings to you.

In addition to this when registering for a trial or purchasing a subscription we will request your full contact details including your name, company name, telephone number, fax number, email and postal address. This information will be used to fulfil your request and will be held electronically in our database. Your details will be treated in the strictest confidence, but may also be used by us for future marketing communications, unless you specifically request not to receive this type of material.

Furthermore, from time to time, we may ask for additional information about you as part of our on-going market research and customer satisfaction surveys. This information will be used to improve the Lloyd’s Register - Fairplay Ltd web site and our news service products. 

**Users Opt-out Rights**

If you have supplied your email address, postal address, telephone number and/or fax number we may periodically send you details of our new products and services as part of our on-going marketing activities. These details are not distributed to any third parties. However if you decide that you do not wish to receive these types of communication please contact our customer services department so that we can update your records accordingly. 

**Data Security**

We take every precaution to ensure that the information you supply is treated in the strictest confidence. Sensitive payment information, such as credit card details, is encrypted and used only to process a single order. We do not keep your credit card details on file. Yours web browser will display when a page is secure, usually by displaying a key or padlock symbol in the display. You can also check to see when we are using a secure site by the https:// prefix in the address. 

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is written to your hard drive when you visit a website and contains information that enables a server to identify your visit to a website.   
The Lloyd’s Register Fairplay Ltd website, as with most websites, uses cookies to assist in providing advanced features including our search facility. We do not store identifiable information in cookies and do not use cookies for the purpose of tracking users. 

**Statistical Information**

The use of log files enables us to compile aggregate statistical information which is used to improve our services and to supply our advertisers with detailed usage information. These log files do not contain personal information and no identifying items are ever passed to advertisers or third party companies. 

**Access to Data**

You have the right to receive details of what personal information we hold about you on our databases. You should write to us at Lloyd's Register - Fairplay Ltd., Lombard House, 3 Princess Way, Redhill, Surrey, RH1 1UP, United Kingdom stating your name, company name and address and providing details of the services you subscribe to. Please note that a small administrative charge may be made for fulfilling this request.

 **Hyperlinks**

Apart from links to other Lloyd's Register - Fairplay Ltd. web sites, the [**World Shipping Directory online web site**](http://www.wsdonline.com/) **** may also contain links to other external sites. Their inclusion cannot be taken to imply any endorsement or validation by us of their content. 

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy or would like any further information please contact our Customer Services Department at:

**Lloyd's Register - Fairplay Ltd.**  
Lombard House  
3 Princess Way  
Redhill  
Surrey  
RH1 1UP, UK  
Tel: +44 1737 379000  
Fax: +44 1737 379001  
Email: [**customer.services@lrfairplay.com**](mailto:customer.services@lrfairplay.com)
